-去你的！      -別擋路！
-Up yours!   -Get out of the way!
錶不錯吧，兄弟？
Fine time piece, brother?
再見
Goodbye.
"Who's the black private dick
that's a sex machine to all the chicks?
"Shaft
"Damn right
"Who is the man that would risk his neck for his brother man?
"Shaft
"Can you dig it?
"Who's the cat that won't cop out
when there's danger all about?
"Shaft
"Right on
"They say this cat is a bad mother
"Shut your mouth
"I'm talking about Shaft
"Then we can dig it
"He's a complicated man
"No one understands him
"But his woman
"John Shaft"
發生了什麼事，馬蒂？
What's happening, Marty?
同樣是六啊七啊的，謝夫特
Same old sixes and sevens, Shaft.
10分鐘前，有兩個人在找你
Two guys were looking for you like 10 minutes ago.
哈林區來的？
Harlem cats?
我哪知道？在我看來每個人長得都一樣
How the hell should I know? Everybody looks the same to me.
輕鬆點，馬蒂
Take it easy, Marty.
保重，謝夫特
Take care, Shaft.
謝了，兄弟
Thanks, brother.
今天早上糖放太多了
Too much sugar this morning.
寶貝，那就別喝
Then don't drink it, baby.
幾個來自郊區的傢伙正在找你
A couple of dudes from uptown looking for you.
認識他們嗎？
Know them?
不知道姓名
Not by name.
剛開張時，在郊區附近見過他們
Seen them around uptown. Come in here when I was opening up.
他們問起 在哪裡可以找到你
Asked where they could find you.
他們長什麼樣子？
What did they look like?
一個穿著時髦的格子外套，另一個很新潮
One was wearing a funky plaid coat. Other one was sharp.
50元的鞋子。黑外套，灰色喇叭褲
$50 shoes. Black coat, gray flares.
-就這些？    -他們身上有傢伙
-Is that all?     -They had heat on them.
穿格子外套的雙手插著口袋
The one in the plaid coat had his hands in his pocket.
緊拉著他的外套，瞭了嗎？
Pulled his coat tight, you dig?
他腰帶上有沉甸甸的鐵器
Had some heavy iron in his belt.
你左腳的鞋子 腳趾的部位有磨損
You got a scuff on the toe of this left shoe.
幾點了，湯姆？
What time you got, Tom?
8:16
停在擦鞋店的前面，他常在那裡閒逛
Pull over in front of that shoe-shine parlor. He usually hangs out there.
好
Okay.
-要我進去嗎？   -不，我們等一下
-You want me to go in?   -No. We'll wait.
讓自己的鞋子發亮，保證你在外事業成功
Got yourself a nice shine. You can go out and make something of yourself, man.
跟你一樣變有錢和變胖？我們有話直說，寶貝
Go out and get rich and fat like you? We're straight, baby.
有時間嗎，謝夫特？
Got a minute, Shaft?
維克，色情圖片我沒興趣。別煩我
Got no use for no dirty postcards, Vic. Get off my back.
我只是想和你談談。
I just want to talk to you.
打電話給我，你知道我的號碼。
Call me up. You know my number.
我請你一杯咖啡。去公園坐一分鐘？
Come on, I'll buy you a cup of coffee. Go sit in the park a minute?
不行。要說就在這裡說！
Hell, no. Just tell me what you got to say right here!
湯姆，拿兩支雪茄來。你抽哪個牌子？
Tom, go get us two cigars. What kind do you smoke?
想說什麼就說吧
Just say what you've got to say.
來兩枝艾爾加西亞
Get us a couple of El Garcia's.
看，我遲到了
Look, I'm late.
你想交給我什麼？
What are you trying to lay on me?
只是愛，謝夫特。只有愛和同情。
Just love, Shaft. Nothing but love and sympathy.
我們互不相欠。去吧，那個心領了
Then we're even. Go on, get on with it.
我還以為你可能知道 我想知道的事
I thought you might know something I want to know.
似乎在郊區發出沉悶的隆隆之聲
Seems there's been a lot of low, quiet rumbles going on uptown.
我們的人只聞其聲，卻不解其意
Our people have been able to pick up the sounds of it, but not words.
這是因為我們黑人談話一向含糊，隊長
That's 'cause us black folk talk mush mouth, Lieutenant.
我以為我們能解決
I thought we'd get to it.
沒錯。但要我去打探。我只會說“去你的，寶貝”
We did. But, you want me to pigeon. I just said, "Up yours, baby."
為什麼今天早上 哈林區兩個傢伙來到鬧區...
How come two cats from Harlem came downtown this morning...
...要找約翰.謝夫特？
...looking for John Shaft?
他們是黑人弟兄，他們來以便讓我教他們握手
They're soul brothers. They came down so I could teach them the handshake.
他們找到你了？
They find you?
當然，我又沒躲起來
Of course, I wasn't hiding.
如果一有消息，就打個電話給我，我還在第38區
If you find out anything, give me a call. I'm still at the 38th Precinct.
好吧
Right on.
你到底要去哪裡？
Where the hell are you going?
去泡妞。你到底要去哪兒？
To get laid. Where the hell are you going?
那男孩的嘴巴太賤了
That boy's got a lot of mouth on him.
這男孩也夠種，他言出必行
The boy's man enough to back it up, too.
他告訴你什麼？
What did he tell you?
沒有
Nothing.
還得依賴那種人
Got to lean on that kind.
你不必依賴那種人
You don't lean on that kind.
給我一包口香糖
Give me a package of gum.
發出聲響，我就砍了你。後退
Make a noise, I'll cut you. Back up.
-謝夫特先生，有什麼不對嗎？   -這朋友病了
-Something wrong, Mr. Shaft?   -Sick friend here.
吉姆，能幫我們按個電梯嗎？
Jim, can you get us a car up?
這我拿走了
I'll take that.
現在，冷靜，老兄
Now, be cool, man.
你的搭檔在哪裡？
Where is your partner?
打開門。
Open the door.
給你半分鐘 說出你到底要我幹嘛
You've got about a half a minute to tell me what the hell you want with me.
警察會問你為什麼把那婊子扔出窗外
The police will ask why you threw that son of a bitch out the window.
是死是活 他們都會找到你。你他媽說不說？
They can find you dead or alive. Now, what's your goddamn story?
顛仔...
Bumpy...
顛仔說要把你帶去郊區
Bumpy says to bring you uptown.
他要你來搞我嗎？
Did he tell you to mess me up?
我是來帶你的
I was to bring you.
這沒道理
It doesn't make sense.
你到了辦公室，帶著一個生病的朋友
You arrive at your office. You have a sick friend with you.
突然，另一個你不認識的人衝上來，就打起架了
Suddenly, another man you don't know rushes up and a fight starts.
你生病的朋友飛出窗外。為什麼，謝夫特先生？
Your sick friend goes out the window. Why, Mr. Shaft?
去問那個先動手打架的人，賴柏維茲先生
Ask the man who started the fight, Mr. Leibowitz.
你朋友，你只知道他叫“德仔”嗎？
Your friend, the only name you know him by is "Tex"?
-不知姓氏？        -沒錯
-No last name?    -That's right.
我不相信，謝夫特
I don't buy that, Shaft.
你所知的應不止這些。比如說，為什麼打架了
I think you know more than that. Why the fight started, for instance.
推測和如何證實，這是兩回事
What you think and what you can prove are two different bags.
你的朋友都帶這種武器晃來晃去嗎？
All your friends walk around with weapons like that?
看情況
That depends.
我的黑人朋友不再帶著兔腳閒逛了
My Negro friends don't walk around with rabbits' feet no more.
別跟我耍聰明。我有個簡單的方法
Don't get wise with me. There's a simple way for me to go.
-我會把你關起來！   -我會告你濫捕
-I'll put your goddamn ass in!
-I'll sue your goddamn ass for false arrest.
那個人摔出去了，你要我相信你的說法？
You want me to believe the man fell out the way you said he did?
-我看起來像個傻瓜嗎？   -別問我，我不會當面說
-What do I look like? Some kind of klutz?
-Don't ask, and I won't tell you.
您的執照是市政府和州政府核發的
You're licensed by the city and the state.
持照人在涉及重大案件下，都不該核發執照
No one licensed can afford to be a wise ass where a felony case is involved.
你是說我會失去執照嗎？
Are you suggesting I'd lose my license?
對極了！你最好相信並對我坦承！
You are damn right I am! You better believe it and level with me!
威脅我的生計就是侵犯了我權利，不是嗎？
Threatening my livelihood is a violation of my rights, isn't it?
拜倫...
Byron...
讓我私下跟他談談
Let me have a talk with him in private.
你要去訊問一個攻擊者
You got an assailant to interview.
去吧，我們談過後我會去找你
Start that and I'll join after we talk.
連你也在呼攏我，這件事臭掉了
I think you are b. s.-ing me, too. This thing stinks.
也許是他不喜歡 你所教的握手方式
Maybe he didn't like the handshake you taught him.
這次亂子 你心知肚明脫不了關係吧？
You know you can get your rump in a sling for this mess?
-遲滯，麻煩不少   -維克，你會救我的
-Static, a lot of hassle.  -You'll save me, Vic.
我可以試試
Well, I can try.
假如？
If?
禮尚往來
One hand washes the other.
世界所有的麻煩 都別想讓我替警察唱歌
All the hassle in the world wouldn't make me sing a song to the police.
不可能，寶貝
No way, baby.
被你扔出窗外的那隻貓 是顛仔.喬納斯的奴才
That cat you threw out the window was a flunky for Bumpy Jonas.
隊長，我沒有把貓扔出窗外
I didn't throw no cat out no window, Lieutenant.
顛仔不會高興的
Bumpy isn't gonna like it.
我不在乎他高不高興！你激我幹嘛？
I don't care what he likes! What the hell are you pumping me for?
兩個星期前，我們開始聽到隆隆之聲
Two weeks ago we started picking up rumbles.
-你說過了    -我們知道那不是黑豹幫
-You already said that.   -We know it's not the Panthers.
或是新少主幫。但是，有某事在喧騰
Or the Young Lords. But, something's on the boil.
我想知道這是什麼...
I want to know what it is...
...在我們需要一台新機器來計算屍體之前
...before we need an adding machine to count the bodies.
顛仔想找你去做某件事
Bumpy wants you for something.
他知道發生了什麼事，這就是我想知道的
He knows what's going on. And that's what I want to know.
不是誰，而是什麼事
Not who, just what.
看到你如此關心弱勢民族，讓我黑人的心變暖了
It warms my black heart to see you so concerned about us minority folks.
拜託，謝夫特。跟我扯黑人這種狗屁幹嘛？
Come on, Shaft. What is it with this black shit?
你又沒那麼黑
You ain't so black.
寶貝，你又沒那麼白
And you ain't so white, baby.
好
All right.
你想玩你的黑色重口味
You want to play your super heavy black number.
我就玩我的
I'm gonna play mine.
以目前我們擁有的事證，足以定你的罪！
We can nail your tail for manslaughter with what we've got on you right now!
你可以戲弄賴柏維茲，但你懂法律，你可能會被起訴
You can waltz Leibowitz, but you know the law. You could be charged.
起訴，隊長
Charged, Lieutenant.
是的，而你的執照將被停用
Yeah, but your license'll be suspended.
你將失業六個月
You'll be out of business for six months.
你想被停業六個月？
You want to be out of business for six months?
走在街上
Out on the street.
沒有槍支許可證，六個月！
No gun permit. Six months!
一切都不順的時候，何況顛仔正在找你？
With Bumpy looking for you when all hell's about to break loose?
你想要 就會如願以償
You want it, you got it.
隊長，你嚇死我了
You scare me to death, Lieutenant.
你自找麻煩，不僅自己受害還會血洗哈林區
You're buying trouble not only for yourself, but a blood bath up in Harlem.
你想要那樣？
You want that?
我想問你的，只是我想知道發生了什麼！
All I'm asking you is to let me know what's going on!
不用名字跟地點，只要說什麼事！
No names, no places, just what!
我不是要你出賣誰
I'm not asking you to sell out.
告訴我遊戲的名稱，讓我知道規則
Tell me the name of the game, so I know the rules.
我考慮看看
I'll think about it.
好吧，現在我還能接受
All right, I'll settle for that now.
那替你爭取48個小時的自由，然後我們再談
That buys you 48 hours on the street, and then we're gonna talk again.
你有顛仔的私人電話號碼？
You got the number of Bumpy's private phone?
好
All right.
去吧，賴柏維茲由我來搞定
Take off. I'll see to Leibowitz.
好吧
Right on.
我會去找你
I'll see you.
瞧瞧那個
Look at that.
-打錯了    -別呼嚨我，這號碼沒錯
-Wrong number.   -Don't bull me, I got the right number.
我是謝夫特
This is Shaft.
你怎麼有這支號碼？
How did you get this number?
在他媽地鐵裡的廁所牆上
Off a bathroom wall in the goddamn subway.
我在找你
I'm looking for you.
我有辦公室的
I've got an office.
這是你的
Here you are.
謝謝
Thanks.
請給我一袋栗子。今天好冷，是吧？
Bag of chestnuts, please. Cold as hell today, huh?
是啊。好栗子
Yeah, yeah. Good chestnuts.
多少？
How much?
兩分錢
Two bits.
-給你。輕鬆點       -謝謝
-Here you go. Take it easy.   -Thanks.
嘿，計程車！
Hey, taxi!
到底是什麼事？
What the hell is this?
你的白媽媽！
You white mother!
計程車!計程車!
Taxi! Taxi!
小子說他會在，他就應該在
Cat say he gonna be here, he should be here.
打開
Open it up.
小子說他會在這裡...
Cat say he gonna be here...
...而卻沒有
...and he ain't.
這不應該的，老大
It ain't right, Boss.
我們等一下
We'll wait.
你聽了他的廢話...
You take crap off of him...
...他會給你更多廢話
...he'll give you more crap.
我們等一下
We'll wait.
這算是什麼狗屁...
That's some cold shit...
...把我的人勒羅伊拋出窗外
...throwing my man, Leroy, out the window.
把我的人抓起來，就這樣他媽的扔出窗戶
Just picked my man up, and threw him out the goddamned window.
還要我們站在一邊等著說謝謝
Got us standing around and waiting to say thank you.
很高興你自己進來了，顛仔
Glad you let yourself in, Bumpy.
免得你在大廳閒逛，壞了我的名聲
Give me a bad name, have you hanging around in the hall.
嘿...
Look...
如果下次那個人來這裡...
If the man ever comes down here...
...再來見你...
...again to see you...
...確認你一定會在這裡
...you make sure you be here.
乖乖等著
Waiting.
你佔了我的位子
You're in my chair.
在外面等
Wait outside.
謝夫特，錫恩斯和勒羅伊想跟你比試？
Sims and Leroy tried to muscle you, Shaft?
對
Yup.
勒羅伊的事 我不會計較
Well, I got no grudge about Leroy.
別叫我感激你
I couldn't give a damn.
我有一份工作要給你
I got a job for you.
我不想當人的嘍囉裸，顛仔
I'm not on the hustle, Bumpy.
是偵探的工作
A detective job.
-哪一種？   -你這種的，你接下吧
-What kind?   -Your kind. You take it.
別騙我，你在說什麼？
Don't jive me. What are you talking about?
有人綁架了我的女兒，瑪希
Somebody kidnapped my daughter, Marcy.
做掉了幾個人
Done in a couple of people.
沒留下要贖金的任何條子。沒人看見什麼
Didn't leave no ransom note or nothing. Nobody saw nothing.
我希望你找到她，這是這他媽的工作
I want you to find her. That's the fucking job.
警察可以免費幫你做
The police do that for free.
不適合我。你知道我不能找警察
Not for me. You know I can't go to the cops.
你想要我嗎？
And you want me?
王牌偵探
The spade detective.
是的，我想要你，因為你是黑人王牌偵探
Yeah, I want you 'cause you're a black spade detective.
我想要你，因為你也涉足白人的地盤！她可能在任何地方
I want you 'cause you got your other foot in whitey's trough! She can be anywhere.
知道誰抓了她？
Got any idea who grabbed her?
許多小貓都恨我入骨
A lot of cats hate my guts.
像你這樣甜蜜，充滿愛心的傢伙？
A sweet, loving dude like you?
對人妻甜言蜜語...
Sweet talking a man's lady...
...在馬廄裡把她的男人打殘了無法上工？
...as you beat her man out of his paycheck in the back room of a horse parlor?
...又開槍打他小孩的手臂？
Feeding his kid shit to shoot in his arm?
誰還能恨你，顛仔？
Who could hate you, Bumpy?
我的寶貝可是跟別人無冤無仇
My baby never sold nothing to nobody. Never took nothing from nobody.
她是個平常的孩子。她要上大學了
She's a straight kid. She's going to college.
無論是誰抓了她，就是想要脅我
Whoever grabbed her, got her to get at me.
想跟我分一杯羹，就應該衝著我來
They have a beef with me, they should come to me.
因此你很守規矩，而別人沒有
So you got a rule that somebody else don't.
你知道的就只有這些？
Is that all you know?
哈林有塊地盤我摸不著，有武裝分子罩著
There's a piece of Harlem I can't get at.
The one them militants got their arm on.
可能是被他們抓走的。她進了一些這樣的東西*
They could have my baby. She's been into some of that stuff.
那群人自稱是“曼巴黨”
Bunch calls themselves the "La Mumba's."
班.巴福德搞出來的
Ben Buford's thing.
我本可以派人去問問他們
I could send my people to ask them.
狗屁
Shit.
這將引起一場槍戰，結束時就會一堆死貓
It'd come to a shootout and when it's all over, a bunch of dead cats.
也許他們已殺了瑪希
And maybe they'd kill Marcy.
是啊，是你這個爸爸引起的
Yeah, you're Papa pimp to them.
他們想傷害你 就跟他們想傷害警察一樣
They want to see you burn as bad as they want to see the police burn.
但綁架女人，這就太過分了
But kidnapping sisters, that ain't their thing.
抓人的目的，無非就是想要錢
The only reason anybody grabs anybody for is money.
哈林還有那些幫派 這麼急著要錢 不惜抓了我的寶貝？
What other bunch in Harlem needs money bad enough to grab my baby?
既然你這麼以為，我有沒涉足白人地盤又有何干？
If you believe that, what's all this about me having a foot in whitey's trough?
我說他們抓了她，可沒說是把她藏在哈林
I said I think they had her. I didn't say they had her in Harlem.
他們不會傻到把她帶到郊區
They ain't dumb enough to take her someplace uptown.
還是很模糊
It don't lay right.
如果我知道是誰抓的，我還來找你幹嘛？
What the hell you think I need you for if I knew who had her?
我是在猜測
I'm guessing.
如果不是他們抓的，沒關係
If they don't have her, all right.
也許他們知道一些端倪
Maybe they know something.
我一無所知
I got nothing.
就是這項工作，謝夫特。
That's the job, Shaft.
你接受，還是不接受？
Will you take it, or no?
我每小時50美元
I get $50 an hour.
雜支另計
Plus expenses.
而且不能問我開銷的用途
And no questions asked about how I spend it.
就依你的
You got it.
我可以隨心所欲的採取任行動
I get a free hand to move any way I want.
只要你能找到我的寶貝
You find my baby.
我只要求這個
That's all I want.
我帶錢來了
I got money.
你就去花吧
You spend it.
而你要找到她
And you find her.
那夠你開始進行了
That'll get you started.
什麼時候能收到你的消息？
When will I hear from you?
只要我有東西可說
When I got something to say.
還有一件事：
One more thing:
要是派個帶槍的傢伙跟蹤我，我會殺了他，再找你算帳！
You send another cat after me with a gun,
I'll kill him and I'll come looking for you!
我會宰了你，顛仔
And I'll get you, Bumpy.
你最好相信
You believe it.
假惺惺*
Fake mother.
“黑人生而自由”
"Black man born free "
你見過班.巴福德嗎？
You seen Ben Buford around?
“世道應是如此
"The way it's supposed to be
“束縛他的鏈條 難以察覺
"Chains that bind him are hard to see
“除非你陪我走一段路
"Unless you take this walk with me
“他住的地方
"The place where he lives
“有很多名字'貧民窟'”
"It's got plenty of names 'Slums"'
班.巴福德曾住過這裡。他還住這兒嗎？
Ben Buford used to live here. He live here anymore?
沒有，幹嘛？
No, why?
我在找他
I'm looking for him.
我也是。他欠我六個月房租
I am, too. He owes me six months' rent.
輕鬆點
Take it easy.
“找任何工作 都很困難
"Any kind of job is hard to find
“這意味著領救濟金的隊伍變長了
"And that means an increase in the welfare line
“犯罪率也節節上升
"Crime rate is rising too
“如果你餓了，你該怎麼辦？
"If you are hungry, what would you do?
“房租已過期兩個月了
"Rent is two months past due
“而建物正在傾倒
"And the building is falling apart
“小男孩要不到一雙鞋”
"Little boy who needs a pair of shoes "
你好女士。我在找一個叫班.巴福德的，認識他嗎？
Hello, ma'am. I'm looking for a guy named Ben Buford. You know him?
是的，我認識
Yeah, I know him.
-他最近在這附近嗎？      -不久
-Seen him around here lately?   -Not in a long while.
“有些兄弟得了大量現金
"Some of the brothers got plenty of cash
“角落裡的小雞見錢眼開
"Chicks on the corner gonna see to that
“有些喜歡吸煙，有些喜歡大麻
"Some like to smoke, some like to blow
“甚至有些用了50元毒品精神恍惚
"Some even strung out on a $50 jones
“有些想逃避現實
"Some are trying to ditch reality
“透過這些，如此飄飄然
"By getting so, so high
“只是你發現 永遠無法觸摸天空”
"Only to find out that you can never touch the sky"
我在找班.巴福德，見過他嗎？
I'm looking for Ben Buford. You seen him around?
不，沒見到他
No, I ain't seen him.
謝謝。
Thanks.
知道今天出了什麼號碼嗎？
Know what the number was today?
“每個星期天清晨
"Every Sunday morning
“我可以聽到老姐妹說著
"I can hear the old sisters say
“哈利路亞，哈利路亞
"Hallelujah, hallelujah
“相信主
"Trust in the Lord
“他會開條道路
"He'll make a way
“我希望他聽到他們的祈禱
"I hope that he hears their prayers
“因為在靈魂深處 他們相信
"'Cause deep in their souls they believe
“總有一天他終將結束
"Someday he'll put an end
“這所有的痛楚
"To all this misery
-“那是在         -蘇爾斯維爾
- "That's in      -Soulsville
“蘇爾斯維爾”
"Soulsville "
-還好吧？     -老兄，還順利吧？
-What's happening?    -Man, how's it going?
見過班？
Seen Ben?
班？哪一個班？
Ben? Ben who?
班.巴福德，你知道我的意思
Ben Buford. You know who I mean.
嘿，伙計，我不認識班.巴福德
Look, man, I don't know no Ben Buford.
二十塊
$20.
班.巴福德。
That Ben Buford.
他躲在阿姆斯特丹的某個地方，710
He's holed up on a place on Amsterdam, 710.
哪間公寓和什麼時間？
What apartment and what time?
三樓。 9點開會
Third floor. There's a meeting at 9:00.
我無法保證
I can't guarantee it.
我剛聽到一隻貓告訴另一隻貓
I just heard some cat tell another cat.
他們和班一起參加了這場行動
They're both in the movement with Ben.
是的，保持輕鬆，寶貝
Yeah, well, stay loose, baby.
你沒事吧？
You all right?
寶貝，你還好嗎？
Baby, are you all right?
我該像是台機器。這樣就沒感覺了
I got to feeling like a machine. That's no way to feel.
過來吧，寶貝
Come here, baby.
今天下午有一位來自郊區的訪客
Had a visitor from uptown this afternoon.
你要吃什麼？
What're you having?
加芥末和洋蔥的熱狗
A dog with mustard and onions.
不
No.
不要洋蔥
Hold the onions.
冷了，對吧？
Cold, huh?
約翰，你幹了什麼？
Well, John, what did you get?
我泡到妞了
I got laid.
郊區，兄弟。阿姆斯特丹街。慢慢來。我還早
Uptown, brother. Amsterdam Avenue. Take your time. I'm early.
冠軍，你輸了嗎？
Champ, you lost?
沒有
No.
你住在這裡？
You live around here?
是啊
Yeah.
你看起來很冷。
You look cold.
吃點東西
Get something to eat.
哎呀，謝謝，先生
Gee, thanks, mister.
沒事，冠軍
Okay, champ.
-那是誰？    -約翰.謝夫特，班
-Who is it?    -John Shaft, Ben.
除非你想吸引更多人，最好把前門那一對分開
Unless you want more visitors, better split up that pair out front.
叫一個在地下室門口把風
Put somebody on the basement door.
你怎麼找到我的？
How did you find me?
不難。你有一個大嘴巴
Wasn't hard. You got a big mouth.
-別亂來，伙計       -你別亂來，男孩
-Cool it, man.   -You cool it, boy.
別讓你的嘴惹麻煩
Don't let your mouth get your ass in trouble.
-我跟你無話可說    -別耍我
-I got nothing to say to you.   -Don't jive me.
-我們在街頭一起混了很久   -陳年老事了
-We've put in a lot of street time together.
-That was a long time back.
我不再認識你了
I don't know you no more.
老兄，患難之交是你忘不了的
A lot of hard years, man. The kind you don't forget.
我給你一分鐘說出你的來意
Now, I'm gonna give you one minute to say what you came here to say.
然後從你進來的那扇門出去，否則我會攆你出去
Then you go back out that door you came in or I'll throw you out.
認識瑪希.喬納斯嗎？
You know Marcy Jonas?
-是啊，幹嘛？    -知道她在哪裡嗎？
-Yeah, why?   -You know where she is?
-你什麼意思？     -有人抓走她
-What do you mean?   -Somebody grabbed her.
顛仔認為也許是你
Bumpy thinks maybe it was you.
我們不做那種事
We don't do that kind of thing.
此事你有所了解嗎？
You know anything about it?
湯姆，你的一分鐘到了。出去！
Tom, you used up your minute. Get out!
不要“湯姆”我，老兄！
Don't "Tom" me, man!
-槍在哪裡？       -這裡沒有
-Where are the guns?    -None here.
真該死的！
I'll be goddamned!
桑尼！桑尼！
Sonny! Sonny!
他們來了！
They're coming!
-在屋頂上？    -是啊。走！
-Up on the roof?    -Yeah. Go!
他死了
He's dead.
快，快！
Come on, come on!
別上屋頂，走這邊！
Not the roof, this way!
退後
Stand back.
-這是什麼？    -一切都會好起來的
-What is this?   -Everything will be fine.
-這是什麼？       -去那邊保持安靜
-What is this?   -Go over there and be quiet.
一切都沒事，女士。不用擔心
Everything's okay, ma'am. No need to worry.
抱歉你的門
Sorry about your door.
這該夠了吧
That'll take care of it.
你出賣了我們，老兄！
You set us up, man!
拜託，年輕人
Young man, please.
別那樣做
Don't do that.
不要再威脅我！別叫我叛徒！
Don't ever threaten me again! And don't call me Judas!
來吧，現在沒時間計算死人。快！
Come on. It's no time to count your dead. Come on!
看
Look.
來吧！
Come on!
就邊，這邊！
This way, this way!
你的人？
One of yours?
-不是     -可能是一個眼線
-No.    -Probably a finger man.
你領導那場革命時，白人最好站著不動...
When you lead that revolution, whitey better be standing still...
...因為你再跑也沒用了！
...'cause you don't run worth a damn no more!
我們別再跑了，老兄
We're done running, man.
那我們是在幹嘛，老兄？
What the hell do you call this, man?
我得搞清楚，他們在追你 還是追我
I got to find out if they're after you or me.
我把你交給一些朋友。他們是普通人
I'll leave you with some friends. They're straight people.
因此，你不要跟他們隨便開玩笑
So don't you lay any of that Uncle Tom jive on them.
這關係很複雜，我拼湊不起來
I don't know what's connected to what. I can't piece them together.
接電話
Answer that.
發生後才過半個小時
It's only a half an hour since it happened.
我哪能這麼快就有線索？
How could I have something this soon?
他在另一條線上
He's on the other line.
我才不會費心去擔心...
I'm not paid enough to worry...
...專員或市長在想什麼！
...about what the Commissioner or the Mayor thinks!
那是謝夫特，你想跟他說話嗎？
It's Shaft. You want to talk to him?
我有一通電話，可能是些消息。稍等
I got a call. I might have something. Hold on.
不，還是我打給你好了
No, better I call you back.
我想見你
I'm coming to see you.
你一直都沒幫我
You've been holding out on me.
我會等。聽著，幾隻貓在哈林被殺了
I'll wait. Listen, several cats were killed in Harlem.
你知道這件事嗎？
You know anything about it?
我就在那裡，隊長
I was there, Lieutenant.
督察在家，回電給他。說我去追查一條線索
The Captain's at home. Call him back.
Tell him I left to chase down a lead.
-你要去哪裡？  -不一定，只要別讓他煩我
-Where are you going?   -Nowhere. Just get him off my back.
有個報社記者想來採訪
A reporter from the News wants an interview.
要他打電話給督察，讓那老混蛋忙一下
Tell him to call the Captain. Serves the old bastard right.
這是情報部門給的清單
This is that list from the intelligence section.
這些照片怎麼樣？
What about the pictures?
他們正忙著湊起來，說要五分鐘
They're getting them together now. Said about five minutes.
謝夫特下來了，叫他馬上進來
Shaft's coming down. Send him right in.
迪娜會把你的床鋪好。老兄你怎麼不睡一覺？
Dina'll get you a bed made up. Why don't you get some sleep, man?
放著一些死去的兄弟在那裡躺著
Got some dead brothers laying out there.
這不是我該來的地方
And this ain't where I should be.
在發現他們的死因前，這是你唯一能待的地方！
Till we find out why they're dead, this is the only place for you to be!
你的想法像個白人！
You think like a white man!
你不用腦筋！你想找死嗎？
You don't think! You want to get wasted?
如果會死就算了！
If that's what it takes!
馬文正在睡覺。
Marvin's sleeping.
我會想出該怎麼做，然後明早再來接你
I'll find out what I can and pick you up in the morning.
你認為這樣我就欠你人情，你就錯了
If you think I'll owe you for this, you're wrong.
我又沒圖你什麼！
You got nothing I want!
那女孩的房間給你用
You can have the girls' room.
我得出去。有備份鑰匙嗎，我回來就不用叫醒你？
I got to go out. Got an extra key so I don't wake you when I come back?
這也可以打開樓下的門
This'll open the downstairs door, too.
注意你的言行
Watch your mouth.
我想說什麼 就說什麼
I'll say anything I want.
這房子裡不行。在這裡你不會
Not in this house. Not here, you won't.
拿椅子坐
Have a chair.
我不喜歡你的椅子
I don't like your chair.
你什麼都沒幫我，維克。
You gave me nothing, Vic.
有人摔出我的窗戶，你就想用誤殺關我...
You want to lock me up for manslaughter 'cause someone went out of my window...
...那就關吧
...go ahead.
你沒資格談交易
You got no deal.
那我也沒東西可以給你，那是事實
I have nothing else to give you, then. That's straight.
你現在有什麼？
What do you got now?
首先是一個問題。
One question first.
能指認那些帶機槍的傢伙 都被滅口了！
Anyone who could've identified those guys with machine guns got wiped out!
是嗎？
Yeah?
班.巴福德的五個人，也許是那個指責你的人。
Five of Ben Buford's people and probably the guy that fingered you.
我？你確定是我嗎？
Me? Are you sure it's me?
我敢肯定，如果我知道這些人是黑人還是白人。
I'd be sure if I knew if the guys were black or white.
我告訴你他們80-20。
I'd make it 80-20 they were after you.
但是顛仔可能肯定會告訴你。
But Bumpy could probably tell you that for sure.
只要說出你得到了什麼，伙計。
Just say what you got, man.
一些可能適合的事情。
A few things that may fit.
你還記得我曾告訴過你，顛仔在哈林將他的船員加倍嗎？
Do you remember I told you that Bumpy was doubling his crews up in Harlem?
所以？
So?
所以，市中心我們有一些遊客。
So, downtown we get some visitors.
來自洛杉磯的三個人，兩個來自鳳凰城，一個來自Decatur的人，lllinois ...
Three guys from LA, two from Phoenix, a guy from Decatur, lllinois...
...來自費城的四個人總共大約15個我們確定的。
...four guys from Philly. Altogether about 15 that we're sure of.
特別的人，對吧？
Special guys, huh?
所有人都懷疑是黑手黨的槍支。
All suspected being guns for the Mafia.
剛進城。
Just got into town.
他們大多數住在村里的一家酒店。參觀景點。
Most of them staying at a hotel in the Village. Taking in the sights.
是嗎？
Is that it?
不，還有一件事。
No, one thing more.
來自哈林的幾個帥哥去了澤西島。
A couple of dudes from Harlem go across to Jersey.
試圖綁架一些黑手黨大佬。他們吹了它。
Try to kidnap some Mafia bigwig. They blew it.
他們殺了這個傢伙的跑步者。
They killed the guy's runner.
但這名男子說，他的跑步者在佛羅里達釣魚。
But the man says his runner was in Florida on a fishing trip.
-看起來像戰爭來了。-這是一件壞事。
-Looks like war coming.   -It's a bad thing.
黑手黨對抗顛仔。它的引擎蓋罩在內側。
Mafia against Bumpy. It's hood against hood, on the inside.
在外面，它是白色的黑色。
On the outside, it's black against white.
如果這件事打破了，我們可以在百老匯有坦克和部隊。
We could have tanks and troops on Broadway if this thing breaks open.
是的，你有一個觀點。
Yeah, you got a point.
這是我們的一些訪客的樣子。
This is what some of our visitors look like.
這是一個美好的時光。
Be a good time for it.
什麼？戰爭？
What? War?
在佛羅里達釣魚。
Fishing down in Florida.
如果我知道顛仔聘請你的話，這可能會有所幫助。
It might help if I knew what Bumpy hired you for.
-他說他做了。-他做到了。
-Never said he did.   -He did.
說是或否，這違背了我的道德觀。
It's against my ethics to say yes or no.
-他讓你當場，謝夫特。-他做了什麼？
-He put you on the spot, Shaft.   -He did?
維克，你是一個非常聰明的高加索人。
You're a very wise Caucasian, Vic.
我會在這的。如果我不是，請在家給我打電話。
I'll be here. If I'm not, call me at home.
那是一種安慰。
That's a comfort.
-你好？ -你好寶貝。
-Hello?      -Hello, baby.
我等了
I waited up.
-抱歉，我做不到。-有問題嗎？
-Sorry, I can't make it.   -Got problems?
是的，我有幾個。
Yeah, I got a couple of them.
我天生黑了，我天生貧窮。
I was born black and I was born poor.
我愛你。
I love you.
是的，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
別緊張。
Take it easy.
嘿...
Hey...
起床。
Get up.
我們有一個人要看。
We've got a man to see.
是啊。
Yeah.
看看你是誰，好嗎？
See who that is, will you?
這是謝夫特
It's Shaft.
讓他進來
Let him in.
-我和顛仔約好了。-我知道這一切。
-I have an appointment with Bumpy.   -I know all about it.
在你看到這個男人之前我必須先看看你是否乾淨。
I've got to see if you're clean before you can see the man.
那麼最好再給自己六個助手。
Better get yourself six more helpers then.
這就是它的完成方式。
That's how it's done.
誰搜索你？
Who searches you?
沒有人。
Nobody.
然後得到同一隻貓來搜索我們。
Then get the same cat to search us.
在你進去之前我必須看看你是否有槍。
I've got to see if you got a gun on you before you go in.
告訴顛仔我們在這裡。來吧，班
Tell Bumpy we were here. Come on, Ben.
威利，你現在會讓他們走路嗎？
You gonna let them walk now, Willy?
顛仔會有你的尾巴。
Bumpy'll have your tail.
在這兒等一下，我會打電話給那個男人。
Wait here, I'll call in to the man.
你想要什麼，威利？
What do you want, Willy?
-謝夫特和一些傢伙在這裡。-發送給他們。
-Shaft's out here with some dude.   -Send them in.
他不會讓我看看他們是否乾淨。
He won't let me see if they are clean.
讓他們進來吧。
Let them in.
繼續，你聽到了他的聲音。
Go on, you heard him.
聽著，白雪公主...
Listen, Snow White...
...我們遲早會糾結。
...we're gonna tangle sooner or later.
你聽到我說的了嗎？
Did you hear what I said?
你為什麼不停止玩自己？
Why don't you stop playing with yourself?
你不會做狗屎！
You ain't gonna do shit!
你是一個謹慎的幽靈，顛仔
You're a cagey spook, Bumpy.
謝夫特先生，你騎著一匹高大的馬。
You ride a tall horse, Mr. Shaft.
這是班.巴福德。昨晚你的小朋友花了他五個朋友。
This is Ben Buford. Your little caper cost him five friends last night.
-我們會把它從你的屁股裡拿出來，皮條客。-你推我一點點。
-We'll take it out of your ass, pimp.   -You're pushing me a little far.
我發現了一些東西，顛仔。
I found out some things, Bumpy.
你知道是誰抓住你的女兒，而不是班或他的人...
You knew who grabbed your daughter, and that it wasn't Ben or his people...
...當你把我所有的東西放在我辦公室的時候。
...when you laid all that jive on me in my office.
我告訴過你，沒有任何說明。我還是不知道誰有她。
I told you, there was no note. I still don't know who has her.
你撒謊，伙計！
You're lying, man!
現在，直接處理它們，或者根本不處理它們！
Now, deal them up straight, or don't deal them at all!
你從黑手黨那裡抓起了麻煩。
You grabbed the dope hustle up here from the Mafia.
給自己做了一些大麵包。
Made yourself some big bread.
現在，黑手黨想要進入你。
Now the Mafia wants to move in on you.
所以呢？
So what?
所以，黑手黨抓住了你的女兒。
So, the Mafia grabbed your daughter.
你知道的。
You knew it.
當你僱用我時，你就知道了。
You knew it when you hired me.
是啊。
Yeah.
你試圖抓住一個進行交易。
You tried to snatch one for a trade.
但你那些狡猾的朋友在那裡吹了它。
But your flunky friends out there blew it.
他們燒了一些孩子。錯過了我們想要抓住交易的人。
They burned some kid. Missed the man we wanted to grab for a trade.
然後你想要喧囂老謝夫特
Then you wanted to hustle old Shaft.
我雇了你一份工作。我騙了你，但我從來沒騙過你。
I hired you for a job. I conned you, but I never lied to you.
我的寶寶被抓了。
My baby was grabbed.
你會讓她回來的。你買了這筆交易。你會活著的。
You'll get her back. You bought that deal. You're gonna live with it.
寶貝，不是這些價格。
Not at these prices, baby.
我告訴你它的成本，成本。
I told you what it costs, it costs.
很多大肆宣傳的黑人給你帶來的錢，皮條客！
A lot of hyped-up black people give you that money you're spending, pimp!
男孩，你不要試圖胡扯我嗎？我們都在喧囂中。
Don't you try to bullshit me, boy. We're all on the hustle.
我賣廣告，塗料和數字。
I sell broads and dope and numbers.
你賣垃圾和藍天。這是完全相同的遊戲。
You sell crap and blue sky. It's all the same game.
你知道黑手黨的貓會跟著我來，不是嗎？
You knew the Mafia cats would come after me, didn't you?
但它並沒有動搖我。
But it doesn't shake me up.
他們採取了一個很好的行動來取消我的前線人物。
They made a good move to take out my front man.
他們可能會再試一次。我會。
They'll probably try again. I would.
你一直在用我，顛仔。格蘭格我
You been using me, Bumpy. Suckered me.
沒關係。我們面對面站著。
That's okay. We stood face to face.
但是，我想知道你為什麼要我和班聯繫。
But, I want to know why you wanted me to hook up with Ben.
因為你需要一支軍隊讓我的寶寶回來。
'Cause you're gonna need an army to get my baby back.
班有一個。
Ben's got one.
我的人民在哈林區之外不值得去。
My people ain't worth a damn outside of Harlem.
如果你認為我冒一些兄弟的風險...
If you think I'd risk some of the brothers...
...只是因為你的女兒是黑人，你錯了，伙計。
...just 'cause your daughter's black, you're wrong, man.
我們需要錢。
We need money.
我有很多兄弟姐妹在監獄裡。
I got a lot of brothers and sisters in jail.
設定價格。
Set a price.
一萬美元頭。
$10,000 a head.
這就是這位謙遜的政府為了保險而在陸軍中支付一隻貓的原因。
That's what the honky government pays a cat in the Army for insurance.
每人10,000美元。
$10,000 a man.
這是我們的價格。
That's our price.
行。
All right.
你告訴我你願意為瑪希佈置那種麵包嗎？
You telling me you're willing to lay out that kind of bread for Marcy?
伙計，別跟我說吧。
Don't jive me, man.
我總能得到更多的錢。
I can always get more money.
我只有一個孩子。
I only got one baby.
-這意味著你已經為他昨晚失去的男人欠他5萬美元。
-That means you already owe him $50,000 for the men he lost last night.
行。
All right.
我們可以從監獄裡找到很多兄弟姐妹。
We can get a lot of brothers and sisters out of jail with that.
他需要多少人？
How many of his you'll need?
取決於黑手黨是否會收取贖金。
Depends on whether the Mafia will take a ransom.
-他們想要哈林，沒什麼。-不是你的。不再。
-They want Harlem, nothing less.   -It ain't yours to give. Not anymore.
我是不是，不是他們的。
Mine or not, it's not gonna be theirs.
我所要做的就是找出他們把她帶到家的地方。
All I gotta do is find out where they've got her and bring her home.
而已。
That's it.
如果他的價值1萬美元，我的價值2萬美元。
If he's worth $10,000, I'm worth $20,000.
你得到了，COD。
You got it, COD.
現在一半，我把她帶回家的一半。
Half now, half when I bring her home.
所有！
All!
馬上！
Right now!
一半，這是我做的最好的。
Half, that's the best I'll do.
你只是被吵了，顛仔
You just been hustled, Bumpy.
今晚交錢。
Deliver the money tonight.
我會讓我的男孩們放棄它。
I'll have my boys drop it off.
按照這些價格，你吹它，謝夫特，我不會喜歡它。
At these prices, you blow it, Shaft, I'm not gonna like it.
一點兒都沒有。
Not even a little bit.
我以為錢對你來說無關緊要。剛剛讓寶寶回來
I thought the money didn't matter to you. Just getting your baby back.
金錢總是很重要。
Money always matters.
這是我下車的地方，伙計。
This is where I get off, man.
有一點我們必須直截了當。如果談到戰鬥，我們會??按照自己的方式行事。
One thing we got to get straight. If it comes to a fight, we do it my way.
對於那種麵包，兄弟們會玩。
For that kind of bread, the brothers'll play.
只要你記得我們欠他們五個。
As long as you remember we owe them five.
我說，我的方式！
I said, my way!
我會打電話給你。
I'll call you.
-嗨，老兄！嘿，比利？過來。
-Hey, man!    -Hey, Billy? Come here.
-幫我個忙。 -當然。
-Do me a favor.    -Sure.
-到我的地方然後打開...
-嘿，不，伙計。我已經打開了。
-Go up to my place and turn on the...
-Hey, no, man. I've already turned on.
不，比利，打開燈。
No, Billy, turn on the lights.
燈。
Lights.
-大約兩分鐘，好嗎？ -得到它了。
-About two minutes, okay?   -Got it.
我們怎麼樣，愛？
How are we doing, love?
真好。不要惹麻煩。
That's nice. Don't make any trouble.
-Johnny！-你說什麼，羅利？
-Johnny!    -What do you say, Rollie?
華麗的外套！
Gorgeous coat!
讓我接管酒吧一段時間怎麼樣？
How about letting me take over the bar for a while?
20美元我不會做任何事情。
There's nothing I wouldn't do for $20.
玩得開心。
Have funzies.
你準備好了。
You look ready.
好的。蘇格蘭威士忌和水。
Yeah, okay. Scotch and water, both.
在房子裡，男士們。
On the house, gents.
由於房子正在購買，我將有一個。
And since the house is buying, I'll have one.
致無名欄的心地善良的老闆。
To the big-hearted owner of the No Name Bar.
他是否知道他是慷慨的。
Whether he knows he's generous or not.
那都是酒！
That's all booze!
好吧。
Right on.
所有的酒。百萬分之一。
All booze. One zillion percent.
你好？
Hello?
堅持，稍等。
Hold on.
不，他不在這裡。對。
No, he ain't here. Right.
那裡，店主？
Ho there, innkeeper?
兩個杜松子酒和補品，還有聖母瑪利亞...
Two gin and tonics, and a Virgin Mary...
...對於moi。
...for moi.
我口渴。焦渴。
I'm thirsty. Parched.
那邊有個女孩...
There's a girl over there...
...黑頭髮和時髦的胸部...
...with the dark hair and the groovy boobs...
如果你有興趣的話，你真的打開了她。
You really turn her on, if you're interested.
我沒死。
I ain't dead.
她的朋友Valerie說她對我的身體很熱。我告訴她我是同性戀。
Her friend, Valerie, says she's hot for my body. I told her I was gay.
你知道她說的話嗎？她讓我理順。
You know what she said? She'd straighten me out.
她是這樣說的。
That's what she said.
我可愛是不夠的，她希望我扮演角色。
It's not enough that I'm lovely, she wants me to play character parts.
帶有刺激性胸部的那個叫做琳達。
The one with the titillating boobs is named Linda.
男人不能單腿行走。
Man can't walk on one leg.
討厭獨自喝酒。
Hate drinking alone.
維克，私人專線。
Vic, private line.
嘿，可愛的寶貝？
Hey, sweet baby?
這是你的愛人。
This is your lover man.
這到底是誰？
Who the hell is this?
兩個甜蜜的猜測。
Two sweet guesses.
你，謝夫特？
That you, Shaft?
你打賭你的可愛自我。而且我已經準備好了。你能挖一下它麼？
You bet your lovely self it is. And I'm ready. Can you dig it?
遇到了麻煩？
Got troubles?
-我得到你想要的。 -你在哪？
-I got what you want.   -Where are you?
村里沒有名字欄。
No Name Bar in the Village.
在簡街。
On Jane Street.
-你想讓我做什麼？-把你美麗的自己帶到這裡。
-What do you want me to do?   -Haul your beautiful self down here.
那裡有多少？
How many are there?
大約兩個。
About two.
我會關閉，然後我們會去看看我的墊子。
I'll close up and we'll go over to my pad.
你走進那扇大門，我現在就關門了。
You walk in that front door, I'll close up right now.
-我會在幾秒鐘內開車。
-這就是我想听到的。
-I'll have a car there in a few seconds.
-That's what I want to hear.
這附近有很多鬆散的東西？
A lot of loose stuff around here?
執事是一個人可以處理的。
All a man can handle, deacon.
你在看什麼？
What are you looking at?
走開。
Get lost.
去做點什麼。
Go do something.
我的舉止在哪裡？
Where are my manners?
我甚至沒有向你們介紹自己。
I didn't even introduce myself to you gentlemen.
我叫約翰.謝夫特。
My name is John Shaft.
凍結！
Freeze!
給我一條毛巾。
Throw me a towel.
有兩個。我們在這裡很慷慨。
There's two of them. We're generous around here.
也不是那麼壞。
It's not so bad.
這是你到這裡的一個不錯的墊子。
It's a nice pad you got here.
我要上樓洗澡。我馬上就回來。
I'm going upstairs to take a shower. I'll be right back.
我等不及了。
I just couldn't wait.
-你說什麼，維克？ -'早上。
-What do you say, Vic?   -'Morning.
他們倆都有槍支，攜帶它們的許可證。
Both of them had guns, licenses to carry them.
許可證稱，“珠寶快遞員”。
"Jewelry couriers," the licenses say.
底特律人。
Detroit people.
-你會把它們鬆開嗎？ -我沒有選擇。
-Will you turn them loose?   -I have no choice.
他們會離開小鎮。
They'll leave town.
你會有陌生人找你，而不是他們。
You'll have strangers looking for you, not them.
我可以和他們私聊嗎？
Can I have a private talk with them?
你現在要對可憐的卡門做些什麼？給他癌症？
What you'll do to poor Carmen now? Give him cancer?
你低下頭，安頓下來。
You busted his head, settle.
我想了解他對城市更新的看法。
I want to find out his views on urban renewal.
行。
All right.
湯姆·...
Tom...
我是在為顛仔.喬納斯說話。
I'm speaking for Bumpy Jonas.
他想確定他的女兒沒關係。
He wants to be sure his daughter's okay.
我的話就是他所要的。沒有電話，也沒有她的來信。
My word is all he'll take. No phone calls and no letters from her.
我得看她。
I've got to see her.
那麼也許他會處理。
Then maybe he'll deal.
我想在這個老鼠洞裡說什麼。
Nothing I want to say in this rat hole.
-人們可能在聽。-這是我們必須承擔的風險。
-People might be listening.   -That's a risk we'll have to take.
現在給我一個號碼，這樣我就可以告訴你我將在哪裡。
Now give me a number so I can let you know where I'll be.
我會在12點30分打電話給你！
I'll call you at 12:30 sharp!
並在12:45在村莊的某個地方見到你。
And meet you at 12:45 somewhere in the Village.
嗨寶貝？
Hey, baby?
-Come here.    -Party's over.
你必須拆分。
You got to split.
其他時間。同樣的感覺，同一個地方。
Some other time. Same feeling, same place.
現在我必須照顧好一些事情。
Right now I've got to take care of some business.
是嗎？
Yeah?
把班放在上面。
Put Ben on.
他睡著了，誰想要他？
He's asleep, who wants him?
喚醒他，這是約翰.謝夫特。
Wake him up, it's John Shaft.
你真的很棒，但...
You're really great in the sack, but...
...之後你很邋..
...you're pretty shitty afterwards.
是嗎？
Yeah?
我正在努力照顧一些生意。
I'm trying to take care of some business.
來吧！
Come on!
班
Ben.
我需要兩個好人。你準備好了嗎？
I need two good men. Are you ready?
是啊。
Yeah.
他們最好是強硬的。
They'd better be tough.
寶貝，請關上門。
Baby, please close the door.
自己關閉，Shitty。
Close it yourself, Shitty.
-告訴我何時何地。-在Cafe？Reggio在村里。
-Tell me where and when.   -At Caf?Reggio in the Village.
-知道它在哪裡？-我會找到的。
-Know where it is?   -I'll find it.
12:30。遲到五分鐘就太晚了。
12:30. Five minutes late would be too late.
我會在那裡。 “再見。
I'll be there. 'Bye.
是嗎？
Yeah?
這是Vic Androzzi。
It's Vic Androzzi.
你到底在這幹什麼？
What the hell are you doing here?
我沒時間聊聊天。
I got no time for chats.
你有時間與卡門聊天
和Patsy今天早上在我的辦公室。
You had time for a chat with Carmen
and Patsy in my office this morning.
你讓我陷入一團糟。
You got me in one hell of a mess.
-你有房間被竊聽嗎？ -不，不是我。
-Did you have the room bugged?   -No, not me.
我？我可以轉向其他方式。
Me? I could turn the other way.
聽不到我聽到的。
Not hear what I heard.
這是我聽到的那個大耳朵的督察
It's that big-eared Captain I got who was listening.
他認為他聽說你在討論綁架問題。
He thinks he heard you discussing a kidnapping.
他認為黑手黨參與其中。
He thinks the Mafia's involved.
他知道顛仔.喬納斯參與其中。
And he knows Bumpy Jonas is involved.
告訴他然後問顛仔。
Tell him to ask Bumpy then.
是啊，我做了。
Yeah, I did.
但他想問你。
But he wants to ask you.
現在。在車站。
Now. At the station.
糟糕的時機，對吧？
Lousy timing, right?
要帶我進去？
Gonna take me in?
如果我找到你，我會的。
I will if I find you.
你在家嗎？
Are you home?
一定不行。
Hell, no.
這太糟糕了。
That's too bad.
回家後給我打電話。
Call me when you get home.
我會。
I will.
“親自動手，Shitty。”
"Close it yourself, Shitty."
這是謝夫特。現在直截了當！
This is Shaft. Now get this straight!
我將於12:45在McDougall街的Cafe Reggio。
I'll be at Cafe Reggio on McDougall street at 12:45.
-得到它了？ -Reggio，12：45。
-Got it?    -Reggio, 12:45.
對。
Right.
菜單？
Menu?
濃咖啡。
Espresso.
你不想要三明治或其他東西嗎？
Don't you want a sandwich or something with it?
只是濃咖啡。
Just espresso.
我希望你不喜歡檸檬皮。
I hope you don't like lemon peel.
放手吧。
Let it go.
我想你喜歡它。我會去找你的。
I think you like it. I'll go get you some.
我總是忘記檸檬皮。
I always forget the lemon peel.
我正在尋找一位名叫約翰.謝夫特的黑鬼。
I'm looking for a nigger named John Shaft.
你才找到他，哇！
You just found him, wop!
坐下。
Sit down.
我得帶你去看望一位女士。來吧。
I have to take you to visit a lady. Come on.
我還沒吃完濃咖啡。
I haven't finished my espresso.
你為什麼不擁有一些？
Why don't you have some?
也許他們會在裡面放一點大蒜，
如果你很好
Maybe they'll put a little garlic in it,
if you're nice.
不用了，謝謝。但你繼續前進。
No, thanks. But you go ahead.
我們甚至有時間為你提供靈魂食物。
We've even got time for you to have your soul food.
濃咖啡？
Espresso?
不用了，謝謝。
No, thanks.
收下。
Keep it.
謝謝，寶貝。
Thanks, baby.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
來吧。
Come on.
在你之後，伙計。
After you, man.
你住在這裡
You stay here.
你繞過後面，留意胡同門。遠離視線。
You get around the back, keep an eye on the alley door. Stay out of sight.
如果他們出來我們怎麼辦？
What if they come out our way?
你跟著他們。嗯，你回來找我。現在移動吧！
You follow them. Remmy, you come back for me. Now move it!
無噪音。現在，直接回答我。
No noise. Now, answer me straight.
沒有謊言也沒有騙局。
No lies and no con.
你有多少男人和她在一起？
How many men you got in there with her?
二。
Two.
好的。
Okay.
當我告訴你的時候，你打開那扇門就像這把槍一樣要把頭吹開。
When I tell you, you open that door like this gun was about to blow your head off.
沒有信號或你走了。得到它了？
No signal or you're gone. Got it?
是啊。
Yeah.
杜松子酒！
Gin!
打開它。
Open it.
把她弄鬆或者他走了。
Turn her loose or he goes.
-告訴他們讓她鬆散。-他不會。
-Tell them to turn her loose.   -He won't.
他不會開槍，瑪希，來這裡。
He won't shoot, Marcy, come here.
你無能為力，謝夫特。
There's nothing you can do, Shaft.
除了回哈林並告訴顛仔，他的小女孩很好。
Except go back to Harlem and tell Bumpy his little girl is fine.
-當我離開時，她離開了我。-不管怎樣，謝夫特。
-When I leave, she leaves with me.   -No way, Shaft.
她是我們的王牌。你永遠不會放棄你的王牌。
She's our ace. You never give up your ace.
可能你是對的。
Maybe you're right.
我應該把你帶到郊區，然後把你轉到顛仔。
I should take you uptown and turn you over to Bumpy.
改變主意，你現在就可以走了。
Change your mind, you can walk right now.
你試著帶走那個女孩或我，你已經死了。
You try to take the girl or me along, you're dead.
你試圖告訴我他們會打擾你去找我？
You trying to tell me they'd blow you away to get me?
那就對了。
That's right.
我中途相信你。但是，你是我的王牌，所以我得打電話給你。
I halfway believe you. But, you're my ace, so I got to call you.
現在唯一能讓你活著的是...
The only thing that's keeping you alive right now is...
...你必須足夠健康地告訴哈林區那個黑朋克...
...you got to be fit enough to go tell that black punk in Harlem...
...他有24個小時可以交易，或者他有一個死去的女兒！
...that he's got 24 hours to deal or he's got a dead daughter!
一場戰爭！
And a war!
你聽到了嗎？
You hear me?
來吧，我們走吧！
Come on, let's go!
我們走吧！
Let's go!
後門。
Back door.
來吧。
Come on.
來吧！
Come on!
你沒事吧？來吧。
You all right? Come on.
來吧。
Come on.
你沒事吧？
You all right?
讓我離開這裡。
Get me up out of here.
這個地方會在一分鐘內和警察發臭。
The place'll be stinking with cops in a minute.
抓住那些槍。我們離開這裡吧。
Grab those guns. Let's get out of here.
-Ellie！艾莉，開放！ -是！
-Ellie! Ellie, open up!   -Yes!
天哪！發生了什麼？
My God! What happened?
他被槍殺了。
He's been shot.
把他放在沙發上。
Put him on the couch.
不想在電話裡告訴你。
Didn't want to tell you on the phone.
艾莉，打電話給薩姆。
Ellie, call Sam.
-你需要一個真正的醫生，寶貝。我說，打電話給薩姆。
-You need a real doctor, baby.   -I said, call Sam.
簡單。
Easy.
刀。
Blade.
接通電話。
Get on the phone.
我們需要更多的兄弟。這次有槍。
We gonna need some more brothers. With guns this time.
顛仔將處理運輸。
Bumpy'll handle the transportation.
約翰尼，不得不帶你去。
Had to bring you to, Johnny.
除非你告訴我你受傷的地方，否則無法解決其他問題。
Can't fix anything else, till you tell me where you hurt.
牆到牆，山姆。
Wall to wall, Sam.
艾莉，給我那個電話。
Ellie, give me that phone.
-那些男孩？-八點
-Get those boys?    -Got eight.
知道他們帶她去哪兒了嗎？
Know where they took her?
其中一個兄弟盯著他們。他現在正在看這個地方。
One of the brothers tailed them. He's watching the place now.
後退怎麼樣？
What about the back exit?
一切都很酷，寶貝。別擔心。
Everything's cool, baby. Don't worry.
你碰到了火車嗎？
Did you run into a train?
你可以得到它。你完成後我很快就起床了。
Tight as you can get it. I got to get up soon as you're done.
該死的，那些是一些堅強的白人男孩。
Damn, those were some tough white boys.
你會有一個地獄般的時間。
You're gonna have one hell of a time.
在右手腕上扭傷不好。
Got a bad sprain on that right wrist.
錄下它吧。
Tape it.
該死的，該死的。你覺得我是什麼人，一個業餘愛好者？
I did, damn it. What do you think I am, an amateur?
山姆，工作太好了。我甚至沒有感覺到。
Too good of a job, Sam. I didn't even feel it.
錯號碼。
Wrong number.
男人，切開垃圾。這是謝夫特。我看到了瑪希
Cut the crap, man. This is Shaft. I saw Marcy.
她還好嗎？
Is she all right?
-死了，但沒關係。
-Scared to death, but okay.
我需要三輛計程車，位於第九和華盛頓的拐角處。
I need three cabs, on the corner of Ninth and Washington.
-去接一些班的人。 -多久？
-To pick up some of Ben's people.   -How soon?
現在，伙計，現在！
Now, man, now!
好的，你們兩個！外！移動，移動！
Okay, you two! Outside! Move, move!
我們走吧！
Let's go!
綁他們！
Tie them up!
好的，制服在哪裡？
All right, where are the uniforms?
-那是誰？-夜間看門人。他沒事。
-Who's that?   -The night janitor. He's okay.
用他來找出他們讓她進入的房間。
Use him to find out which room they got her in.
-一起來嗎？-是的，馬上。
-Getting it together?   -Yeah, right on.
美麗。
Beautiful.
只是美麗。
Just beautiful.
傑瑞，你好嗎，寶貝？
Jerry, how are you doing, baby?
嗨男孩？
Hey, boy?
發送兩杯咖啡和一杯可樂。
Send up two coffees and a Coke.
玻璃還是吸管？
Glass or a straw?
對於可口可樂。
For the Coke.
把它變成一根稻草。
Make it a straw.
稻草？
Straw?
你聽我說，稻草。
You heard me, straw.
對。
Right.
你是一隻精明的貓，謝夫特。
You're a shrewd cat, Shaft.
你和你的孩子們吹它，我將成為一隻死貓！
You and your boys blow it and I'll be one dead cat!
你們都知道這個計劃。沒有錯誤。
You all know the plan. No mistakes.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
你有，先生。兩杯咖啡，一杯可樂和一根稻草。
There you are, sir. Two coffees, a Coke and a straw.
-我想接受它嗎？ -Whoa。
-Want me to take it in?   -Whoa.
對。
Right.
嘿，謝謝！
Hey, thank you!
-我會見你的。 -好的。
-I'll be seeing you.    -Okay.
閉嘴！
Shut up!
-你們想要什麼？ -你的大衣。
-What do you guys want?   -Your coat.
繩索和挽具。
Rope and harness.
來吧。
Go ahead down.
你聽到了什麼嗎？
Did you hear anything?
沒有。
No.
這該死的東西不會燒得太熱。
This damn thing won't burn hot enough.
你還有別的東西會燃燒嗎？
You got something else in there that'll burn?
這是杜松子酒，伙計。
It's gin, man.
你還有什麼？
What else you got?
汽油。
Gasoline.
來吧！
Come on!
給我一支煙。
Give me a cigarette.
-你知道該做什麼？是啊。
-You know what to do?   -Yeah.
我們離開這裡吧！
Let's get out of here!
來吧！
Come on!
我們走吧！
Let's go!
安德魯齊，在這裡。
Androzzi, here.
維克，你的案子剛剛開放。
Vic, your case just busted wide open.
所以關閉它對我來說。
So close it for me.
男人，切開垃圾。這是謝夫特。
Cut the crap, man. This is Shaft.
“你必須自己關閉它，Shitty！”
"You'll have to close it yourself, Shitty!"